Register of the David Starr Jordan Papers, 1794-1950
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1894-1947
  - American Friends of German Democracy (Folder 9)
  - American Institute of International Law (Folder 10)
  - American League of California (Folder 11)
  - American Neutral Conference Committee (Folder 12)
  - American Social Hygiene Association (Folder 13)
  - American Union Against Militarism (Folder 14)
  - American Vigilance Association (Folder 15)
  - Amnesty (Folder 16)
  - Angell, Norman (Folder 17)
  - Arlington Cemetery (Folder 18)
  - Armenia (Folder 19)
  - Armenian and Syrian Relief Commission (Folder 20)
  - Armistice Day (Folder 21)
  - Australia (Folder 22)
  - Austria (Folder 23)
  - Bainbridge, Oliver (Folder 24)
  - Balfour, Arthur (Folder 25)
  - Balkans (Folder 26)
  - Belgium (Folder 27)
  - Berwick, Edward (Folder 28)
  - Big Brother Committee (Folder 29)
  - Bok Peace Plan (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Boy Scouts (Folder 2)
  - Briand, Aristide (Folder 3)
  - British Institute of International Affairs (Folder 4)
  - Bryan, William Jennings (Folder 5)
  - Bulgaria (Folder 6)
  - Burbank, Luther (Folder 7)
  - Bureau International de Fédérations d'Instituteurs (Folder 8)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray (Folder 9)
  - California (Folder 10)
  - California Psychical Research Society (Folder 11)
  - Catholic Church (Folder 12)
  - Cecil, Robert, Sir (Folder 13)
  - Censorship (Folder 14)
  - Central Organization for a Durable Peace (Folder 15)
  - Chesterton, G. K. (Folder 16)
  - Children of American's Fund (Folder 17)
  - China (Folder 18)
  - China Commerce Club (Folder 19)
  - Chinese-American League of Justice (Folder 20)
  - Citizen's Amnesty Committee (Folder 21)
  - Cobb, Frank I. (Folder 22)
  - Cole, George M. (Folder 23)
  - Commercial Travelers Mutual Accident Association (Folder 24)
  - Commission for Relief in Belgium (Folder 25)
  - Committee for Democratic Control (Folder 26)
  - Committee for the Relief of Russian Student Refugees (Folder 27)
  - Committee on Public Information (Folder 28)
  - Committee on Selective Immigration (Folder 29)
  - Commonwealth Club of California (Folder 30)
  - Comstock, Anna B. (Folder 31)
  - Conference on American Oriental Problems (Folder 32)
  - Conference on National Expenditure (Folder 33)
  - Congrès Sociologique International, October, 1922 (Folder 34)
  - Constantinople (Folder 35)
  - Corda Fratres (Folder 36)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution (D.A.R.) (Folder 37)
  - David Starr Jordan Fund, The (Folder 38)
  - Democracy (Folder 39)
  - Disarmament (Folder 40)
  - Dotation Carnegie pour la Paix (Folder 41)
  - Eccentric literature (Folder 42)
  - Economic aid (Folder 43)
  - Economic conditions - Europe (Folder 44)
  - Economics (Folder 45)
  - Education (Folder 46)
  - Egypt (Folder 47)
  - Eibun-Tsushin (Folder 48)
  - Emergency Peace Federation (Folder 49)
  - Emerson, Ralph Waldo (Folder 50)
  - Eugenics (Folder 51)
  - Europe (Folder 52)
  - European War, 1914-1918 (Box 61, Folder 1-2)
  - European War, 1914-1918 - Reparations (Folder 3)
  - Evolution (Folder 4)
  - Fédération Abolitionniste Internationale (Folder 5)
  - Femmes Socialistes Françaises contre la Guerre (Folder 6)
  - Fluegel, Ewald (Folder 7)
  - Foerster, Friedrich W. (Folder 8)
  - Ford Peace Commission (Folder 9)
  - Ford Peace Expedition, 1915 (Folder 10)
  - Foreign Policy Association (Folder 11)
  - France (Folder 12)
  - Fried, Alfred H. (Folder 13)
  - Friends of German Democracy (Folder 14)
  - Gardiner, Alfred G. (Folder 15)
  - Gardner, Nathaniel L. (Folder 16)
  - General Committee on the Limitation of Armament (Folder 17)
  - General Defense Committee (Folder 18)
  - Germans in America (Folder 19)
  - Germans in Hungary (Folder 20)
  - Germans in Mexico (Folder 21)
  - Germany (Folder 22)
  - Goldsborough, T. Alan (Folder 23)
  - Great Britain (Folder 24)
  - Greece (Folder 25)
  - Hart, Albert Bushnell (Folder 26)
  - Hawaii (Folder 27)
  - Hearst, William R. (Folder 28)
  - Herron, G. D. (Folder 29)
  - Hillquit, Morris (Folder 30)
  - Hoover, Herbert C. (Folder 31)
  - Ichthyology (new species of fish, discovered by David Starr Jordan, named for Jessie Knight Jordan) (Folder 32)
  - Illinois Vigilance Association (Folder 33)
  - Immigration (Folder 34)
  - India (Folder 35)
  - Indians of North America (Folder 36)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations (Folder 37)
  - Institute of World Unity (Folder 38)
  - International Committee of Women for Permanent Peace (Folder 39)
  - International Congress for the Study of the Principles of a Durable Peace (Folder 40)
  - International Congress of Women (Folder 41)
  - International economic relations (Folder 42)
  - International Free Trade League (Folder 43)
  - International Help to Workers of the Spirit (Folder 44)
  - International law (Folder 45)
  - International Magna Charta Day Association (Folder 46)
  - International organizations (Folder 47)
  - International Peace Congress (Folder 48)
  - International relations (Folder 49)
  - International relief (Folder 50)
  - International Service Bureau (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - International trade (Folder 2)
  - Internationalism (Folder 3)
  - Ireland (Folder 4)
  - Japan (Folder 5)
  - Japan Society of America (Folder 6)
  - Japanese-Americans (Folder 7)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (Folder 8)
  - Joint Amnesty Committee (Folder 9)
  - Kellogg, Paul U. (Folder 10)
  - Kemal, Mustafa (Folder 11)
  - Kibuchi, Dairoku (Folder 12)
  - Kings and rulers (Folder 13)
  - Knight, Austin M., Admiral (Folder 14)
  - Knight, Charles S. (Folder 15)
  - Korea (Folder 16)
  - Labor (Folder 17)
  - Lansing-Ishii Agreement (Folder 18)
  - Lazarovich-Hrebelianovich, Prince and Princess (Folder 19)
  - Lea, Homer (Folder 20)
  - League for Democratic Control (Folder 21)
  - League of Free Nations (Folder 22)
  - League of Nations (Folder 23)
  - League of Nations Association (Folder 24)
  - League of Nations Union (Folder 25)
  - League of Oppressed Peoples (Folder 26)
  - League to Enforce Peace (Folder 27)
  - Levinson, Samuel O. (Folder 28)
  - Lodge, Henry C. (Folder 29)
  - Luxemburg (Folder 30)
  - MacDonald, James A. (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Macedonia (Folder 2)
  - Mahan, Alfred, Admiral (Folder 3)
  - Marshes (Folder 4)
  - Marvin, Fred R. (Folder 5)
  - Massachusets Amnesty Committee (Folder 6)
  - Mencken, H. L. (Folder 7)
  - Menschheit, Die (Folder 8)
  - Meredith, George (Folder 9)
  - Metric system (Folder 10)
  - Mexico (Folder 11)
  - Militarism (Folder 12)
  - Military service, Compulsory (Folder 13)
  - Military training (Folder 14)
  - Miller, J. J. M. (Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 16-18)
  - Money (Folder 19)
  - Motion pictures (Folder 20)
  - National Civic Federation (Folder 21)
  - National Civil Liberties Bureau (Folder 22)
  - National Council for Limitation of Armaments (Folder 23)
  - National Council for Prevention of War (Folder 24)
  - National Council of Women of Norway (Folder 25)
  - National defense (Folder 26)
  - National Economic League (Folder 27)
  - National Education Association (Folder 28)
  - National Peace Conference (Folder 29)
  - National Peace Council (Folder 30)
  - National Security League (Folder 31)
  - National War Relief Committee (Folder 32)
  - National Women's Peace Party (Folder 33)
  - Nautical training schools (Folder 34)
  - Naval training (Folder 35)
  - Navy League (Folder 36)
  - Netherlands (Folder 37)
  - New Student, The (Folder 38)
  - Newspapers (Folder 39)
  - Nineteenth Century and After, The (Folder 40)
  - Order of the Golden Rule, The (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Organisation Centrale pour une Paix Durable (Folder 2)
  - Oriental News and Comment (Folder 3)
  - Oriental Survey Organization (Folder 4)
  - O'Ryan, John F. (Folder 5)
  - Osterreichische Voelkerbundliga (Folder 6)
  - Pacifism (Folder 7)
  - Paderewski Testimonial Fund, Inc. (Folder 8)
  - Page, Walter H. (Folder 9)
  - Palmer, Mitchell (Folder 10)
  - Palo Alto, California (Folder 11)
  - Pan-American Congress, Washington (January 6, 1916 and March 26, 1923) (Folder 12)
  - Pan-American Federation of Labor (Folder 13)
  - Panama (Folder 14)
  - Panama Canal (Folder 15)
  - Panama-Pacific International Exposition (Folder 16)
  - Patriotism (Folder 17)
  - Peace
    - General
      - Memoranda, reports, proposals, petitions (Folder 18-19)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 20)
      - Newspaper clippings (Folder 21)
      - Printed material (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Peace Plans (Folder 2-3)
  - People's Council of America (Folder 4)
  - People's Legislative Service (Folder 5)
  - People's Reconstruction League (Folder 6)
  - Philippines (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Pinchot, Amos (Folder 2)
  - Poetry, songs, prayers (Folder 3)
  - Poland (Folder 4)
  - Political campaign, 1920 (Folder 5)
  - Political prisoners (Folder 6)
  - Politics and government (Folder 7)
  - Portland, Oregon (Folder 8)
  - Prohibition (Folder 9)
  - Propaganda (Folder 10)
  - Prostitution (Folder 11)
  - Prussia (Folder 12)
  - Public works (Folder 13)
  - Publishers (Folder 14)
  - Raskob, John J. (Folder 15)
  - Rathenau, Walter (Folder 16)
  - Reed, James A. (Folder 17)
  - Religion (Folder 18)
  - Rendtorff, Karl G. (Folder 19)
  - Rivière, A.-Joseph (Folder 20)
  - Rome, Italy (Folder 21)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore (Folder 22)
  - Ruhr Valley - Allied occupation (Folder 23)
  - Russell, Bertrand (Folder 24)
  - Russia
    - General (Folder 25)
    - Foreign policy - Asia (Folder 26)
    - History - Revolution, 1917-1921 (Folder 27)
  - Sacco-Vanzetti Case (Folder 28)
  - Sain, Charles MacKnight (Folder 29)
  - Scott, Harvey W. (Folder 30)
  - Sewall, May Wright (Folder 31)
  - Shidehara, Kijuro (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Slake, Frank H. (Folder 2)
  - Socialism (Folder 3)
  - Society of Friends (Folder 4)
  - Stanford University
    - Commencement programs, invitations, etc. (Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 6)
    - Publications
      - Magazines (Folder 7)
      - Newspapers (Folder 8)
      - Yearbooks (Folder 9)
  - Strong, Anna Louise (Folder 10)
  - Taft, William Howard (Folder 11)
  - Tahiti (Folder 12)
  - Taxes (Folder 13)
  - Tirpitz, Alfred von (Folder 14)
  - Treaties (Folder 15)
  - Trevelyan, Charles P. (Folder 16)
  - Turkey (Folder 17)
  - United States
    - General (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - American Relief Administration (Folder 2)
    - Army (Folder 3)
    - Civil service (Folder 4)
    - Department of Justice (Folder 5)
    - Department of Labor (Folder 6)
    - Department of the Interior - Office of Indian Affairs (Folder 7)
    - Foreign relations
      - General (Folder 8)
      - Germany (Folder 9)
      - Japan (Folder 10)
      - Mexico (Folder 11)
      - Russia (Folder 12)
    - Foreign service (Folder 13)
    - History - 1865-1898 (Folder 14)
    - House of Representatives (Folder 15)
    - Immigration (Folder 16)
    - National anthem (Folder 17)
    - National Defense Act, 1916 (Folder 18)
    - Navy (Folder 19)
    - Neutrality (Folder 20)
    - Population (Folder 21)
    - Senate - Committee on Military Affairs (Folder 22)
  - Universal Society of Social Improvement (Folder 23)
  - Venereal disease (Folder 24)
  - Vigilance League of America (Folder 25)
  - Villard, Oswald G. (Folder 26)
  - Wall Street (Folder 27)
  - War (Folder 28)
  - War debts (Folder 29)
  - Water resources development (Folder 30)
  - Wesley, John (Folder 31)
  - White, William Allen (Folder 32)
  - Wilhelm II, Kaiser (Folder 33)
  - Wilson, Woodrow (Folder 34)
  - Wolfe, Edward I. (Folder 35)
  - Women (Folder 36)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (Folder 37)
  - Women's Pan-American Conference, 1924 (Folder 38)
  - World Affairs Group (Folder 39)
  - World Campaign to End War (Folder 40)
  - World League for Democracy (Folder 41)
  - World Peace Association (Folder 42)
  - World politics (Folder 43)
  - World's Congress of International Associations (Folder 44)
  - Young, Robert (Folder 45)
  - Young Democracy, The (Folder 46)
  - Young Men's Christian Associations (Y.M.C.A.) (Folder 47)
  - Yugoslavia (Folder 48)
- MISCELLANY, 1910-1929
  - Clippings. Scrapbooks of bound writings, family memorabilia, letterbook, notebook, photograph of faculty of Stanford University, 1910-1914 (Box 69)
  - Medals (Box 89)
    - "Imperial Order of the Rising Sun of Double Rays," awarded to David Starr Jordan by the Japanese Government, 1922
    - "Order of the Sacred Treasure, Second Class," conferred on David Starr Jordan by the Emperor Meiji, 1911 (Box 90)
  - Plastic relief of David Starr Jordan, 1929 (Box 90)
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1911-1922
  - Certificates
    - "Order of Sacred Treasure" and the "Order of the Rising Sun" (in Japanese) (Map-case Map case)
    - "Imperial Order of the Rising Sun of Double Days" (letter in English) (Box 91)
    - "Order of the Sacred Treasure, Second Class," (translation and letters in English by the Acting Consul General of Japan)
  - Drawings and paintings (Box 91)
  - Five large scrapbooks on international relations and war (On-shelf On Shelf)
- AUDIO-VISUAL MATERIAL
  - See photo card catalog (Photo-file Photo file)